Hallelujah!
There is a wonderful name Jesus
There is no other name I know
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Happy Palm Sunday!
You may be seated, thank you.
Hallelujah.
Many of us don’t know the purpose of life.
Sometimes, you see people lamenting because of their challenges,
crying because of their setback, complaining and worrying.
What is the purpose of life?
Your purpose of life will never be fulfilled without heat of trial.
Tell your neighbour, "Your purpose of life will never be fulfilled without heat of trial. "
It could be setback, affliction, or whatever.
Tell your neighbour, “What is your worry?
What are you lamenting about?
What are you complaining about?
Your purpose of life will never be fulfilled without that."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There is no other way.
So, prepare yourself for the battle.
Prepare yourself for what?
For the battle.
Life is not perfect.
We are in the world but we are not part of it.
We live in a world where the enemy will never allow God’s purpose to be fulfilled in our lives -
you need to put up a fight.
That is why we need God.
That is why we are here.
The song says, "This world is not my home"
There is no way you fall asleep, forgetting yourself...
We live in a world where the enemy will never allow God’s purpose to be fulfilled in your life -
we need to put up a fight.
This is why we need God.
This is why we are here.
Let me share a revelation with you.
Success is not about your weakness;
success is not about your setback.
It is about what Jesus did for us at the Cross.
He made us fit.
Tell your neighbour, “Jesus made me fit”.
It’s a past tense event; it’s a past tense victory.
You are fit.
Jesus made us fit for God.
Hear what He said on the Cross.
He said, “Father, forgive them”.
The word, “them” includes both the offender and the offended, the accuser and the accused.
Once your sin is forgiven, what else?
You are fit.
Tell your neighbour, “Once my sin is forgiven, what follows? Fitness for God .”
Tell your neighbour, “Jesus made me fit for God”.
If you have lost that fitness, there is grace for you.
Spend your time with Him, at His feet, by meditation.
Meditate on His Word, the Word of God.
Those of you that want to re-dedicate yourself...
Because we are fit already; it is a past tense victory.
When I give you this, you may probably lose it, but we are looking for it again.
Listen to me.
Meditate on the Word of God and turn it over and over in your heart.
That is...
Meditation brings revelation
and revelation brings conviction
and conviction brings real movement.
You say, “I’m a child of God”.
If truly you are a child of God, that is real movement
and real movement is power steps.
A real movement brings power.
Real movement, "I'm a child of God" - power steps...
Power steps are steps with intent and purpose.
So, because it is not a true conviction; that is why power does not follow.
Where God talks, power talks.
I know many might have lost that grace of being born-again.
It is a past victory.
So, here you can come back to the table again, with God.
Meditate on the Word; turn it over and over in your heart.
Meditation brings conviction and conviction brings real movement.
That is, "Yes! We are children of God." - it means you become a solider of God.
You are not alone; God is for you, on your side, behind all.
You with God are majority - that is a real movement.
If God is for you, what follows?
What follows?
That is it.
The promise of God brings hope and expectation.
I can see the hope and expectation.
You are expecting something!
I can see you have received promise.
If I'm talking to you...
The hope is so great.
The way you laugh; if someone is expecting something, you will see it in his movement, in his appearance.
When you are expecting something, you are going to the office -
somebody promised you million of dollars, and you know that is sure,
"Good afternoon, sir"...
But if you doubt what you are going to receive and you are not sure if you receive it...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
But what I'm seeing now is very sure.
So, I want to congratulate you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is huge.
This is a real movement, like I have said.
Real movement brings excitement.
I mean real excitement.
Real excitement; look what happened to Peter when Jesus was on the sea.
Peter said, "Lord, I want to come to You".
Because the real movement, you can see...
"I want to come to You."
He said, "Come!"
You can see an attempt to come on his own first because Jesus wants to see whether he is genuine.
Our genuine willingness plus God’s ability brings about the result.
You can see him with that genuine desire.
This is what I have seen today.
I'm just prophesying to you.
The way out for you has come!
(Amen!)
Yes. Now, what are we talking about?
That which you are worried about,
that which you are complaining about
and that which you are lamenting about -
the purpose of life will never be fulfilled without that.
Our walking with the Lord – both good and hard times alike.
Good and what?
Hard times.
Like I have said.
Success is not about your setback;
success is not about your failure.
It is about what Jesus did for you at the Cross.
All the way to Calvary He went for me
He went to set me free
You listen to that?
He went to do what?
What else again?
Tell your neighbour, “Success is not about your failure;
success is not about your setback.
Success is about what Jesus did for you at the Cross.
He made you fit for God."
He made me fit to receive, to talk to God, to eat with God."
He went on the Cross to set you free.
So, what else?
Spend your time with Him and learn at His feet.
How do we learn at His feet?
By meditation.
Meditate on the Word; turn it over and over in your heart.
It is not the way we are reading the Bible today.
The Bible is not just a book; it’s an inspiring one.
So, if truly you are a child of God, you talk of real movement
and real movement brings excitement.
Even when there is no food on the table you are excited.
Nobody will even know the difference when there is money in your pocket, and when there is no money
because your life will remain the same.
People will not know.
Because you know; money in the pocket does not make you a child of God,
and lack of money in your pocket does not make you a child of God.
Your vision is different from money in the pocket.
The man that is poor is the man that has no vision.
Can you see?
You can know if this man is a true child of God
because real movement brings excitement and the promise of God brings hope and expectation.
But no hope...
A man without hope - you can see;
the appearance - nothing to write about.
Each time you have a little problem, people around you will know
and each time you have money, people around you will know.
What kind of life is this?
How can your situation dictate your direction, or rule you?
When you are good, you smile, when you are not good you run.
What kind of Christian is that?
What is the difference between you and the others?
Because those are the things that dictate their direction, their life, their mood, their dominion.
Those are the things that dictate their posture.
Ask your neighbour, “What is the difference between you and others?”
Others are happy when there is food on the table.
You are happy when there is money in your pocket.
You are happy when there is food on the table.
How can your situation rule your life?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The difference between us and others is simple:
We are happy when there is money in our pocket
and also we are happy when there is no money in our pocket
because the man that is poor is not the man that has no money but the man without vision.
Think about all this.
Your purpose in life will never be fulfilled without heat of trial.
Tell your neighbour.
(Your purpose in life will never be fulfilled without heat of trial.)
Your purpose in life will never be fulfilled without setback, temptation or affliction.
Overflow Congregation
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Once again, “Happy Palm Sunday!”
I'm happy.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I'm just trying to listen to the sound of your clapping, to see whether...
Thank you.
When you listen to that sound, you can know whether it is a joyful one, pretentious one or pretentious calm.
But the one I'm hearing now... hmm.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes, it is your heart that is clapping.
It's not you.
And when our heart claps, God claps.
So, thank you.
Hallelujah.
So, you are taking this lesson home.
Can somebody talk to me, what lesson are you taking home?
We want just a little counsel, what lesson are you taking home?
Brother, what are you taking home?
What do you hear me saying?
OK, what I'm taking home is that in this life I cannot escape challenges - this is number one.
Number two; I may by poor physically but the real poverty is when I live without a vision.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
That is your lesson - that is wonderful.
Clap for him.
Our father wants to talk.
You listen to that?
He says, it seems, he will not be able to escape challenges.
And when that challenges come, they are meant to prepare him for the future.
- My name is... from Niger State.
- Thank you.
I learned the lesson from your message that there are no successes in life without challenges.
Challenges are just like fertilizers to make you very strong.
Clap for him!
Look at him, look at my brother; he says that challenges are fertilizers.
That is the tonic to our anointing.
Tell your neighbour, "Challenges are like a fertilizer to improve us.
Challenges are like a tonic to our anointing."
You hear that; that's all.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Don't forget; your challenges can be an affliction, hardship, temptation, setback, joblessness.
Try to understand that.
When you know that; yes - you have overcome.
Challenges are tonic, fertilizer.
So, why are we lamenting then?
Why are we worried?
When challenges come, once you worry, the purpose has been defeated.
Debts...
When you are worried, your heart will be in prison at the same time.
Worry imprisons our heart.
When your heart is imprisoned, you cannot communicate with your Heavenly Father.
You need a free heart to communicate, to talk to God.
When you have sickness and you are worried, then the purpose of that challenges has been defeated;
I mean you are in prison.
Once our heart is in prison we are finished.
Don’t worry yourself; leave it for God.
Once you worry, your heart is in prison because a joyful heart is for God.
Take note of this.
OK?
Worry means fear.
The sickness and challenge does not kill the fear of it kills.
The challenge does not kill but the fear of it destroys.
It is the fear of that challenge that destroys us, that destroys our relationship with God.
Fear would take you to occultist, witch-doctor, fear can take one to joining a secret cult.
Fear will make you to begin to look at Jesus in a very bad light.
With fear you cannot read your Bible, you cannot pray - whom are you praying to?
The word fear means worry.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Bible says, in this world there will be what?
Challenges.
Put it that way, “In this world, there will be challenges; cheer up – stop worrying – I have overcome.”
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In this world... this is why I say that the life is not perfect.
In this world, there will be challenges, situation; cheer up - stop worrying, lamenting, complaining -
that is the meaning of "cheer up".
The reason for stopping complaining; "I have overcome for you".
This is why Jesus said, He made us fit – meaning, He has overcome for you.
Once you are fit, you can face it.
Can we hear from our mummy or sister...?
OK.
You just tell us from the different angle.
Good morning.
I have learned that I'm not supposed to live the way others live in the world.
Even if there is no money...
Why you are not supposed to live the way others live?
Because; even if I don't have money in my pocket...
No, because you are a child of God.
Yes.
It is not an issue of money.
When I say, "Your situation is different from others; as a child of God..."
If one has cancer and doctor discovered it by test, "this is cancer", and you are a child of God -
that cancer is different from others.
Other's cancers kill, destroy, but a Christian's that have a cancer - their cancer strengthens their desire.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That situation is to improve him, not to impair him.
Take note of that.
They can say, this man has cancer and this man has cancer.
The question is who is this man and who is this man.
It is not the cancer that matters.
Can't you see what I'm saying?
Success is not about your situation.
Success is not about your setback;
success is not about you.
Who is that man?
That is the question.
It will determine the kind of cancer he has.
Who is this man?
It will determine the kind of situation he has.
This man belongs to others; meaning unbelievers.
When others have that situation; the cancer is a killer - they cannot escape it.
But a child of God with that situation – God is still saying something.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God can use anything to speak to us.
You can be going to work in the morning and suddenly you see a python on the way,
laying on the very road you need to pass - a big one.
And you are a type of a person that is always afraid.
What would you do?
You will even give that python your ID card in your bag, before you run.
Everything; you will just drop it on the python and start running.
And python did not ask you to give him the bag and the money.
After you had dropped it, because of fear, you started running...
God is still saying something; God does not want you to go to work.
If you went to work, something worse would have happened.
But to send you back home, something that can threaten you... like cancer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You start running, you abandon your...
By the time you get home, something will happen in the office.
You say, "Ah! Something happened?"
This is what God is trying to remove you from.
He often uses those things to preserve us, to stop you awhile in order to rearrange you.
Because you are too fast.
You are blessed; God gave you blessing and you received it.
This is a small office, where you are supposed to remain and continue your business.
Because when the money come, you will start opening offices everywhere and it will become a burden to you.
Now, situation may come and the whole office will be closed down, or you yourself will fall sick
and if you cannot run the office while being sick, the office will close down.
That does not mean the end has come.
... but to stop you awhile in order to rearrange you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell us the kind of situation in the past, God might have used...
- Emmanuel!
- OK, thank you.
Good morning.
My name is Albert.
My past situation that God used - I was in prison; that was the time I spent reading the Bible.
That was the time I got to know God and learnt more about God, while I was in prison.
Clap for him.
You listen to that?
Because he is aware that God used that situation to strengthen him, to prepare him, to strengthen his desire
and determination for God, he will never regret.
It is when we regret... this is when we continue to make more mistakes.
But he is thanking God; and he is not even regretting, he is happy - and that situation was not wasted.
God was still saying something.
Clap for him.
Thank you.
Can somebody stand up and tell us the kind of situation God might have used in the past to prepare you
or to rearrange you, or to stop you awhile?
OK.
My name is ... from Ghana.
About two years ago, when I first got into arm forces, everything was rosy.
I passed my first promotional exams.
I got married, when I wanted to get married.
A month after my marriage I had a child, so I thought life would be like that.
But I realised that when I wanted a second child, it wasn't coming.
I started complaining, and feeling anguish.
Then, a time came for me to do my second promotional exams to the next stage;
I tried and I failed the practical part.
This situation made me to go more to church, read more the Bible, seek the face of God more.
To the glory of God, at His appointed time, I did the second try of the practical part and I passed the exam.
At His right time, He has given me a second fruit of the womb.
Listen to that.
So, what is your relationship with God now?
Are you fully persuaded concerning the Word of God?
Now, nothing would take me away from the love of God.
More than before?
More than before.
Thank you.
Now, I seek the face of God more, in all situations.
And don't forget to carry those children along with you.
- Yes, sir.
- OK?
Don't forget to carry those children God has given you.
When it comes to the issue of God, anywhere you step for God, allow them to step with you.
- OK?
- Yes, sir.
That is the greatest legacy you can give to your children.
Yes, sir.
I will.
Our mummy here mentioned two miracles, at first...
Once one is disappointed, worry comes; you begin to worry.
When you are worried, your heart will never be at its best.
Once you are heart is not at its best, you are in prison.
The heart that is in prison cannot communicate with the Heavenly Father.
When you go around; that is the challenge many of us are facing.
When we bring your heart out now, you will see within that heart worry, anxiety, pain of the past, offence.
Such heart cannot see God.
Blessed are the hearts that are pure.
So, these are the challenges we are facing.
And satan is aware of that; the only way he can get you is to make you worried, to make sure that the engine
of your car knocks.
When it is knocked, and it is time to go to church you say, "Ah. No, I cannot go to the church.
The engine of my car is knocked."
And you are forgetting that before you had that car, you were sleeping in the church.
You were even trekking from your house to the church but God has given you a car now
and the engine is knocked; you cannot come to church.
OK, let's listen to...
- Emmanuel!
- (God with us.)
"Alive" example to me.. it was in 2016; I was very sick.
I was taken to hospital.
I was having a stomach problem.
They run a lot of tests.
The doctor said they could not discover what the problem was but they would operate me.
I refused it; I said no.
They asked why.
I said I had a God, "Let me go and meet my God".
Luckily for me I went to...
Can I say something?
Will I believe that you have a God; that's why you refused the operation, or because of fear of death?
No, please - let us talk...
These two questions; this is clear to me because this is what I discover.
No. You tried all means.
Finally, operation was the last option, when they said, "No way"...
But for you to say, "After a lot of tests, they discovered they must do an operation..."
And you said to doctors, "No. I have a God."
That God would have done it first, and you would go for test to see the positive result.
When that trouble was so much, you would have gone to that God, of which you know is an "Alfa and Omega";
He would have done it and you would just go to doctor, "Test me. The sickness is gone."
But in this case, we have done tests, the pain was so much...
Later, they said there was nothing they could do, they had to operate you.
No! I have a God!
Let's hear from you.
So, I...
What later happened to your God?
I went to church and I prayed and I was made whole, I was healed, the pain disappeared.
I didn't take any drug, I didn't go back to the hospital.
There is nothing bad in taking the drug.
But the pain went away.
If you don’t believe God with your tablets, you will not believe God without tablets.
Tell your neighbour, "If you don’t believe God with your tablets, you will not believe God without tablets."
Tell your neighbour!
(If you don’t believe God with your tablets, you will not believe God without tablets.)
This tablet is "nature"...
What is the difference between different juices you put together in the morning,
and the tablet you are talking about?
There is no difference.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is nature, and God is the God of nature.
I want you to clap for my sister because you took us to many areas people want to hear.
Thank you very much.
- You have more to say?
- Yes.
OK, say it.
Another case was...
When I wrote my first JAMB, I couldn't get that score for the course I wanted to do.
OK.
So, I had to pray and fast.
I told God, "This is the course I want to attend. Just help me..."
But that JAMB; you had first choice and second choice.
Yeah, but there is a particular...
Wait! Answer my question.
You know where I'm going.
- You had a first and a second choice?
- Yes.
There is no alternative for our faith.
My first and second choice are the same thing, but I have different...
You know what many choices normally cause?
It cause you not to put all your effort, "You know, if I lose this I will go to this."
But if it is only only one course you apply for, you know there is no other way.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Clap for her.
Thank you, my sister.
The big challenge; what happens to us, happens also to our children.
We always have alternatives...
Some will sit here and say, "Ah. If that pain is not going away, I will go to that place. But today let me stay.
Next week, I will not come here, I will go to another place."
We always have alternatives to our lives.
Alternatives...
Those are the same alternatives that have ruined us today.
... not only us but also our children.
One faith, one love, one God, one Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You listen to me?
One God, one love, one faith, one Holy Ghost.
Alternative...
The whole thing is all over the world today.
I hope you are getting your faith back.
Some faiths are very weak, with what we are hearing now.
Some of our mummies, daddies and those who are sick; you see them with the placard...
Some of you, when you see them with the sickness, affliction, you say, "Ah. It is because of their sin.
Ah. This is why they come to the church."
Ah ah...
A man can be sick in body and yet be a friend of God.
Tell your neighbour.
(A man can be sick in body and yet be a friend of God.)
A man can be sick; that sickness could be anything: cancer, HIV...
Sickness is sickness.
A man can be sick in body and yet be a favourite of Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Today, you see people dying in silence because they don't want people to see them sick.
"What people would say?"
They would say, "They are not Christians. He is not a pastor."
They keep...
They can disclose their trouble to the doctor but to God... no.
A man can be poor and yet be a friend of God.
We should not allow our wealth, blessing, situation, condition to dictate or rule our life.
Be careful; the outcome of your prayer should not affect your faith.
Because you prayed and your prayer is not answered does not mean you do not have faith.
We base our faith on the outcome of our prayer.
People today base their faith on the outcome...
"I don't have faith; that is why my prayer is not answered. I will not pray." - No...
Stop basing your faith on the outcome of your prayer.
Some stand and, "In Jesus' name" - they would say, "This man has so much faith.
Look, he commanded and it happened, but I keep commanding and no way." - No.
Don’t base your faith on the outcome of your prayer.
Tell your neighbour.
(Don’t base your faith on the outcome of your prayer.)
Emmanuel.
My name is ...
In 2016, when papa was telling us about forgiveness; there was a man that started crying at the audience.
It was 14th of February 2016.
He was crying that he have helped people and all of them have failed him.
I was in the overflow congregation in Ghana church.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
After the service I called the friend, but deep inside me I haven't forgiven him, I still bore some grudges in me.
It took me some years.
Last year in December, facing difficulties in my life, I called this friend, but there was no answer.
Deep in me, God asked me to call that friend that had hurt me previously and I didn't forgive him.
I forgave him and went to him.
At that point of my life; everything that I wanted for all those years came back within one month.
Clap for him.
Thank you.
Good.
This is a testimony people need to hear.
You listen to that?
The dividend of forgiveness.
Can you see?
Listen to him.
Forgive and see what follows -
what you have been looking for for many years, what you have been praying for will come.
Forgive and see what follows.
I believe your faith is lifted up.
I will take it once again;
being a child of God is a movement – not just a movement but a real one.
“I am a born again” this is a real movement and a movement brings excitement.
If truly you are a child of God – excitement.
Even when money is not in the pocket, be excited.
When there is no food on the table, be excited.
It honours God when we believe in Him when things look rough.
Things look wrong, when there is no money in your pocket and you believe in Him - it honours Him so much,
more than when there is money in the pocket.
Tell your neighbour, “It honours God more to believe in Him when there is no money in the pocket
than when there is money in the pocket.
It honours God more to believe in Him when there is no food on the table
than when there is food on the table.
Are you with me now?
What am I saying?
It honours Him more whey you believe in Him when you are sick that when you are not sick.
It honours Him so greatly, so much when you are sick and you believe in Him
more than when you are not sick and you believe in Him.
This is what satan has been using to rob us; our blessing.
Once we are sick, we cannot pray.
Once we are sick, faith is gone.
We begin to look at Jesus in a very bad light, "What have I done? Why this sickness?
I'm doing well, I'm going to church, I've stopped smoking, I've stopped lying..."
as if you are the one who stopped that smoking.
Has anyone power to stop smoking or lying?
(No.)
Truth is not our work but lying is our work.
Tell your neighbour.
(Truth is not our work but lying is our work.)
To say the truth is not our work; it is God’s work but to tell lies is our work.
We are very good at it.
No - this is what you should know.
To tell lies - yes, that is our work.
But truth - how can you say, "I stopped smoking"?
To smoke is our work but to stop is not our work; it is God’s work.
Overflow Congregation
To drink is our work.
To stop drinking is not our work; it is God’s work.
Tell your neighbour.
(To stop drinking is not our work; it is God’s work.)
Every, every like that...
To destroy...
Destruction is our work.
To build is not our work; it is God’s work.
How can you say, "Why all this now? I've stopped lying. Why all this sickness?"
Is it your work to stop?
Can you stop?
(No.)
Even if you try to stop on your own...
You stopped smoking on your own; when you sleep you smoke...
You will smoke...
This is what has happened; you smoke in the dream - by the time you wake up you start looking for a cigarette.
I hope you are blessed.
(Amen.)
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service